

LEONARDO J. MACEDO

Software Engineer | SysAdmin | BSS (Telco) Consultant

ABOUT ME

Over 9 years' experience as Business Support Systems (BSS) analyst and IT consultant with broad experience in Applications support Integration, operations, and business support in Telecom domain.

Strong knowledge in ITSM best practices (ITIL framework) mainly focused on Incident Management, Problem Management, Service Availability, and Change Management processes and procedures.

As a last semester M.Sc student, I'm spending most of my time working on my thesis about **Automating ITSM Incident Management process** through Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Machine Learning techniques.

EDUCATION

M.Sc in Software Engineering (In progress) | 2017 - 2019

Faculty of Engineering, University of

B.Sc in Computer Science | 2007 -

São Judas Tadeu Faculty - São Paulo, Brazil

CONTACT

in macedojleo

macedojleo@gmail.com

macedojleo

🥱 macedojleo.github.io

S leonado.macedo

EXPERIENCE

SEP, 2017 - PRESENT

Master degree student

Faculty of Enginering, Universisty of Porto

Presently spending most of my time working on master's thesis "Automate ITSM Incident Management Process" throught Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing (NLTK for Python) technologies and concepts.

SEP, 2009 - AUG, 2014

IT BSS Consultant

Orga Systems

BSS (Business support system) operation/production accountable for automating processes (scripting), customer requests, Incident ticket management, problems (troubletickets), and RFC technical validation role (risk analysis and mitigation, implementation, and validation)

AUG, 2014 - JUN, 2017

IT Specialist

Nextel Telecomunicações

BSCS iX convergent rating engine operation SME, ensuring performance and quality of the technical platform servers and applications besides vendor's, Dev Team, and QA Cooperation in order to guarantee the system availability according to the SLA

SEP, 2014 - AUG, 2017

Production Analyst

Ericsson

Ticket Incidents and defects management providing in a timely manner a definitive, or at least, a contour solution (WA) in order to guarantee system reliability and stability keeping the system uptime according to SLA and KPI metrics.

FREE COURSES

2019	2018	2015
Mastering Ansible (in progress) UDEMY	Python for Engineering NTITEC (FEUP)	Oracle Database 11G Adm Ka Solution
2014	2006	2006
ITIL V3 - Foudantions Ka Solution	Cisco CCNA V3 Senac - SP	Linux System Administrator Senac - SP

OPEN SOURCE AND ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Ansible CI

github.com/macedojleo/DOCKER_ANSIBLE

BDH - Monitorize Unix and Linux FS consuption

https://macedojleo.github.io/BDH/

7th Talk-A-Bit Tech Conference - Porto

http://talkabit.org/

Automate IT Incident Management Process

macedojleo.github.io/Aprendizagem-Computacional-em-ITSM/

CosnFlix - Video Streaming Service

https://github.com/macedojleo/COSNFLIX

Pomar - Organic Food APP

https://gitlab.com/gigantedocil/pomar-mobile-

SKILLS

Development	IT Infrastructure	Languages
Shell Script & AWK	Linux & Unix	English
Python	Docker & Docker Compose	Spanish
Git & GitHub	Oracle SQL	Portuguese
Text Markup Languages	BMC Control-M	